# ANSHUL RAHEJA

Email: anshul.raheja97gmail.com

DOB: 16-Oct-1997

Delhi

## **EDUCATION**

B.tech (CSE)

Dr. Akhilesh Das Gupta Institute of Technology and Management

2016-2020 | CGPA: 8.3

12th

St. George's 2015-2016 | **88.6%** 

10th

St. George's 2013-2014 | **89.3%** 

# **SKILLS**

Technical Skills: React | JavaScript |
CSS5 | HTML | Nodejs | MongoDB |
Java | SQL | Git | Github | OOPS |
Data Structure and Algorithm

**Soft Skills:** Problem Solving | Analytical Thinking | Focused | Persistent | Adaptive

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR**

Volunteer

Josh Talks | June 2019

Part of the Event Management Team for 2 days. My responsibilities were to help the production team in various activities and oversee the smooth running of the shoot.

## Marketing

Entrepreneurship Cell | 2018 - 19

Active Marketing Member in organizing the Annual Internship Fair in my college and bringing various companies onboard as recruiters.

# Operations

Awaaz- Cultural Society | 2016-17 Performed various roles and activities to successfully organize Annual College Fest 2017

## SUMMARY

With over a year of corporate product development exposure with JavaScript, Java, and SQL I'm determined to advance my career in front-end web app development by creating visually appealing and dynamic elements that provide the best user experience possible.

For all of my projects, I'm using Reactjs. I hope to blend my problem-solving and design talents to succeed as a Full-Stack Web Developer

#### MY WORK

Portfolio Website: https://anshulraheja.netlify.app

Github: <u>anshulraheja</u> Linkedin: <u>anshul-raheja</u>

Dev.to (Tech Articles): anshulraheja

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer**

Newgen Software | Feb 2020 - June 2021

- Implementation of Newgen Products.
- Understanding of object-oriented design, data structure, and algorithms.
- Proficiency in the digitization of the Insurance process.
- Execute full software development lifecycle (SDLC) and knowledge of associated issues.
- Deployment of the complete solution.
- Requirement Gathering, Client Interaction & Discover Solution.

Software Used: BPM, ECM, CCM

Tech Stack Used - Java, Javascript, SQL

## INTERNSHIPS

#### **Business Development Executive**

Extramarks Education Pvt Ltd | Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

- Develop strategies to boost a company's sales and overall growth.
- Present the company's product to the customer through phone calls and F2F interaction.
- · Conducting research to analyze client's needs.
- · Summarize the weekly progress and achieve the target.

# **Team Leader**

AIESEC | Feb 2018 - Oct 2018

- Member of Incoming Global Volunteer Department for the 1st guarter.
- Facilitated international student exchanges who worked as volunteers in schools & NGOs across Delhi along with handling two teams who helped in the facilitation and smooth functioning of all processes.
- Experience management and tracking for 10+ volunteers coming to Delhi and looked over the legalities of the exchange including the contracts, exchange product policies, and other relevant matters.

# **PROJECTS**

# **Automatic Image Caption Generator**

Major Project | 2020

A model that uses deep learning/Al technology to form meaningful sentences by interpreting images.

Tech Stack Used - Python

# **Motorcycle Crash Detection and Alert System**

Minor Project | 2019

A device that detects accidents through sensors and acts as an informant to riders close aid in case of emergency.

Tech Stack Used - Java, Android, Arduino Uno programming